Guide to the Sarah Hoskins photographs, 2000-2014 RL.10153
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- The Homeplace, 2000-2014; 1; 3.0 Linear Feet (250) 11x14" Silver Gelatin Prints in 5 flat boxes.
  - The Beasley Sisters, 2007 (Box 4, Print RL10153-P-0235)
    The Beasley Sisters do a comedy routine that is just too funny. Here they are at Zion Hill Days performing. New Zion, KY.
  - High Five, 2006 (Box 4, Print RL10153-P-0236)
    New Zion Days on the lane. New Zion, KY.
  - Young Men, 2011 (Box 4, Print RL10153-P-0237)
    Young men at the Walker family reunion. Columbustown, KY.
  - Queenie and the Crew, 2007 (Box 4, Print RL10153-P-0238)
    The crew out back of Uncle Ernest and Uncle Rufus Talbert's, brothers who lived next door to each other. New Zion, KY.
  - Meeting on the Hill, 2011 (Box 4, Print RL10153-P-0239)
    Juanita Mulder in foreground with Whitney Hughes behind her and Doodle to the far right. They are planning Zion Hill Days. Zion Hill, KY.
  - Basketball Uttingertown, 2003 (Box 4, Print RL10153-P-0240)
    An older vistor to Uttingertown Days watches the young men play basketball behing the lodge. Uttingertown, KY.
  - Sad Boy, 2007 (Box 4, Print RL10153-P-0241)
    James Godfrey seems pretty sad on the hill, Zion Hill Days. Zion Hill, KY.
  - Rev. Hunter Byrd, Frogtown Days, 2003 (Box 4, Print RL10153-P-0242)
    Rev. Byrd walks up the road from visiting his wife's grave before Frogtown Days. It was a bit rainy so it was held in the old Rosenwald school behind New Vine Church. Fort Spring, KY.
  - Ghosts, 2003 (Box 4, Print RL10153-P-0243)
    Beatty kids running in cemetery behind New Vine Baptist Church. Fort Spring, KY.
  - King of the Hill, 2010 (Box 4, Print RL10153-P-0244)
    Kids playing, Zion Hill Days. Zion Hill, KY.
  - Home Court, 2006 (Box 4, Print RL10153-P-0245)
    Raymond Relford moved back from CA and built this next to his home behind his mother's house up on the hill. New Zion, KY.
  - Memorial Day March, 2008 (Box 4, Print RL10153-P-0246)
    Zion Hill residents and family march up the lane to the cemetery they cleared out that had been overgrown to lay flags to honor those fallen soldiers and family. Zion Hill, KY.
  - Alone Loss, 2009 (Box 4, Print RL10153-P-0247)
    Juanita Mulder stands off alone, maybe at the grave of the child she lost. Others pray together. Zion Hill, KY.
  - The Last, 2004 (Box 4, Print RL10153-P-0248)
    Davis Burris watches as they auction off his equipment. He was my friend's uncle, the last black resident in the hamlet. Mayo, KY.
  - Zion Hill Marker Dedication Day, 2008 (Box 4, Print RL10153-P-0249)
    Ponice Raglin Cruse is giving one of the speeches before they unveil the Zion Hill historic marker. Only New Zion had one. Zion Hill, KY.
  - Tears of Joy, 2008 (Box 4, Print RL10153-P-0250)
    Best friends Myrtle B. Hughes and Margaret Raglin shed tears of joy as the historic marker is unveiled in Zion Hill. A proud day that the hamlet is honored. Zion Hill, KY.
- Rosenwald Schools, 2007-2014; 1; Consists of 303 computer files, approximately 10.3 gigabytes.
  The Rosenwald Schools series contains 303 electronic records documenting school buildings built by the Rosenwald Foundation. As Hoskins writes: "In my work each photo project leads to another. The Rosenwalds school is no different. It stems from The Homeplace project. Finding a Rosenwald school is like finding buried treasure. The problem in photographing comes in a number of ways. The first is I am often trespassing and second I am often there at a time of day when the light is not the best." Electronic records are chiefly digital images with a few text documents describing the locations Hoskins visited. The photographs document the schoolhouse buildings themselves exteriors and interiors, as well as nearby structures and occasionally local residents.
  Access restrictions
  Electronic records in this series have been migrated to a library server and digital use copies can only be accessed onsite in the Rubenstein Library Reading Room. To request access, please contact Research Services before coming to use these records.
  - Allen County, Kentucky, 2013; 1; 20 TIFF image files;approximately 0.7 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the Rosenwald school building and nearby church in Allen County. The school building is referred to as Caney Fork School as well as Maynard Rosenwald Colored School.
    - Caney Fork Church, next to Caney Fork School, 2013
    - Light above Caney Fork Church next to Rosenwald School, 2013
    - Caney Fork School, 2013
    - Caney Fork School, 2013
    - Caney Fork Church, next to Caney Fork School, 2013
    - Caney Fork Church, next to Caney Fork School, 2013
    - Caney Fork School, 2013
    - Caney Fork School, 2013
    - Caney Fork School, 2013
    - Caney Fork Church, next to Caney Fork School, 2013
      Door was open to the church and this was what was in there.
    - Caney Fork Church, next to Caney Fork School, 2013
    - Caney Fork School, 2013
    - Caney Fork Church, next to Caney Fork School, 2013
    - Outhouse behind Caney Fork Church, 2013
    - Caney Fork Church, next to Caney Fork School, 2013
    - Caney Fork Church, next to Caney Fork School, 2013
    - Caney Fork Church, next to Caney Fork School, 2013
    - Caney Fork Church, next to Caney Fork School, 2013
    - Caney Fork School, 2013
    - Caney Fork Church, next to Caney Fork School, 2013
  - Berea, Kentucky, 2013-2014; 2; 2 TIFF image files, approximately 0.1 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the restored Berea Consolidated School currently used by Berea College.
    - Berea Consolidated School, 2013
    - Berea Consolidated School, 2014
  - Boydtown, Kentucky, 2012-2014; 3; 9 TIFF image files, approximately 0.3 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the Rosenwald school building in Boydtown, Kentucky. Hoskins writes: "It wasn't until 2013 that I photographed this school. I had been in the church behind it back in 2006 and some other times as well. The church had been closed prior to 2006 and the congregation merged with New Zion which is how I learned about through Rev. Lyle Morton who used to pastor at both. It now stands empty waiting to decide what will happen to it. The school has been a home for a number of years. I spoke with the owner who said she moved out there because it was so quite but is now concerned as the subdivisions in Georgetown are getting closer and closer."
    - Boydtown Rosenwald School, now a home., 2013
      The old Methodist Church is behind it. Rev. Lyle Morton Used to pastor there
    - Boydtown Rosenwald School, now a home., 2013
    - Methodist Church behind Rosenwald School, 2013
    - Boydtown Rosenwald School, 2013
    - Boydtown Rosenwald School, 2013
    - Methodist Church behind Boydtown Rosenwald School, 2013
    - Boydtown Rosenwald School, now a home., 2013
    - Boydtown Methodist Church behind Boydtown Rosenwald School, 2013
    - Boydtown Methodist Church behind Boydtown Rosenwald School, 2013
  - Coletown, Kentucky, 2014; 7; 1 TIFF file, approximately 0.1 gigabytes.
    The image in this subseries documents the Rosenwald school building in Coletown, now used as a home.
    - Coletown School, 2014
  - Cadentown, Kentucky, 2012-2014; 5; 22 TIFF image files, approximately 0.8 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the Rosenwald school building in Cadentown, Kentucky. Hoskins writes: "I have been to this school numerous times over the past 14 years. The first visit was back in the fall of 2001. I remember as it was my first trip after 9/11 in October. The school was empty and in disrepair. The Cadentown Baptist Church which was in front to the school had been sold and had been made into a private residence. Back on that first visit on a early Sunday morning I knocked on the door. There was no answer, I ignored the No Trespassing signs and went around to the back and photographed the school (though I did not know anything about Rosenwald Schools at the time). I also photographed the outhouse but was most intrigued by the cemetery as it was in a strange state. There were red flags posted next to the grave stones and it just felt odd. It wasn't until the next spring that I learned of all the controversy. Apparently the people who bought the church and made it a home did not welcome people visiting the old cemetery and there was talk of moving it. The owners had put a fence up towards the front of their home which is where the signs were the no trespassing signs were posted. I heard stories that it turned pretty nasty. My friend Jonetta Young and her mother Helen who lived down the road in Cadentown fought for a long time to save the school and cemetery as well as halt a new white church that was being built. The white church was across the street from their home and the school. The building of the new church caused flooding to theirs and neighboring homes. Also the white church was tearing up old grave sites. Jonetta hired a "cadaver dog" and the story made the Herald Leader,( the Lexington paper.) I know that I have images of old grave stones that were moved. Kind of like the movie Poltergeist. The new white church eventually went up. The graves paved over for a parking lot. Jonetta moved away with her mother Helen who I heard got Alzheimer's and passed away. She was a lovely woman whose Birthday was close to mine. We always sent Birthday cards and it was Jonetta and Helen Young who introduced me to the Howard sisters. Helen Young had been a student at the Cadentown school, her teacher had been Lena Mae Howard. It was Jonetta and Helen Young who I followed out to meet and photograph the Howard sisters in Uttingertown over 10 years ago. I also photographed Helen Young in front of the school for American Legacy magazine back in 2003. I heard stories that Jonetta had been threatened by people and I believe that to be true as she worked so hard and was such an advocate to save the school and Cadentown. I heard from her once by email out of the blue thanking me for my work I had been doing. I wrote her back thrilled to hear from her but never heard back again. I think it is a tribute to her that the school survived, but I feel so bad that somehow she got lost along the way."
    - Princess Spencer, 2012
      Princess was 92 years old in this photograph. Princess attended this school where her sisiter Lena Mae Howard taught.
    - Princess Spencer and her sister Virginia French, 2012
      Princess was 92 years old in this photograph her sister Virginia 83. Princess attended this school where her sister Lena Mae Howard taught. Virginia did not, here they are laughing.
    - Princess Spencer and her sister Virginia French, 2012
    - Princess Spencer and her sister Virginia French, 2012
    - Princess Spencer, 2012
    - Princess Spencer, 2012
      Princess was 92 years old in this photograph her sister Virginia 83. Princess attended this school where her sister Lena Mae Howard taught. Virginia did not, here they are laughing. This photo was used in a story in Preservation Magazine fall 2012
    - Princess Spencer and her sister Virginia French, 2014
      Princess was 92 years old in this photograph her sister Virginia 83. Princess attended this school where her sister Lena Mae Howard taught. Virginia did not.
    - Princess Spencer and her sister Virginia French, 2014
    - Cadentown School, redone, 2012
    - Cadentown Rosenwald School, redone, 2012
    - Back of Cadentown Rosenwald School, 2012
    - Cadentown Rosenwald School, redone, 2012
    - Cadentown Rosenwald School, redone, 2014
    - Back of Cadentown Rosenwald School, 2012
    - Princess Spencer, 2014
    - Princess Spencer, 2014
    - Princess Spencer, 2014
    - Princess Spencer, 2014
    - Cadentown Rosenwald School, redone, 2012
    - Cadentown Rosenwald School outhouse, 2012
    - Rehabbed Rosenwald School, 2012
    - Rehabbed Rosenwald School, 2012
  - Crittenden, Kentucky, 2012; 8; 3 TIFF image files, approximately 0.1 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document Rice Chapel which stands next to the site of the Dry Ridge Rosenwald school building. Both buildings had been moved to a park in Crittenden. Hoskins writes: "The school was burned, arson was the cause in 2012. The Ku Klux Klan had spray-painted a racial epitaph on the school prior to it being burned."
    - Rice Chapel which stood next to the Dry Ridge Rosenwald school in Grant Park, 2012
    - Rice Chapel which stood next to the Dry Ridge Rosenwald school in Grant Park, 2012
    - Rice Chapel which stood next to the Dry Ridge Rosenwald school in Grant Park, 2012
  - Kerrville, Kentucky, 2014; 18; 1 TIFF file, approximately 0.1 gigabytes.
    The image in this subseries documents the North Middletown Rosenwald school building.
    - North Middletown Rosenwald School, 2014
  - Sadieville, Kentucky, 2008-2014; 28; 31 TIFF image files, approximately 1.1 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the church and Rosenwald school buildings in Sadieville, Kentucky. Hoskins writes: "I learned about Sadieville from my friend Raymond Edwards who was a member of the Jimtown Male Chorus (he passed away in 2007). When he first told me about Sadieville the Baptist church was still going and he and the chorus had gone there to sing. He thought I might be interested in the church and school."
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, pre-rehab, 2008
      Baptist church in background.
    - Sadieville church which is in front of the Rosenwald School, 2008
      Many of the schools where connected and often funded with the help of the church
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, pre-rehab, 2008
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, pre-rehab, 2008
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, 2008
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, pre-rehab, 2008
      Church on right.
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, pre-rehab, 2008
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, pre-rehab, 2008
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, pre-rehab, 2008
      Church in foreground.
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, pre-rehab, 2008
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, after rehab, 2013
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, after rehab, 2013
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, after rehab, 2013
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, after rehab, 2013
      View of Mt. Pleasant Baptist Church
    - Interior of Sadieville school, after rehab, 2013
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, after rehab, 2013
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, after rehab, 2013
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, after rehab, 2013
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, after rehab, 2013
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, after rehab, 2013
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, after rehab, 2013
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, after rehab, 2013
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, 2014
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, after rehab, 2013
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, pre-rehab, 2010
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, pre-rehab, 2010
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, pre-rehab, 2010
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, pre-rehab, 2010
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, pre-rehab, 2010
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, pre-rehab, 2010
      Church on left.
    - Sadieville Rosenwald School, pre-rehab, 2010
  - Richmond, Kentucky, 2014; 27; 1 TIFF file, approximately 0.1 gigabytes.
    The image in this subseries documents the Rosenwald school building in Richmond. At the time this photograph was taken, it had been converted to a building for the Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA).
    - Rosenwald School, now YMCA, 2014
      Shot from the side as light is terrible.
  - Montgomery County, Alabama, 2012; 23; 13 TIFF image files, approximately 0.4 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the Cecil JR Brown Rosenwald school building in Montgomery County, Alabama. Hoskins writes: "I heard about this school on the way home from vacation. I feel it is one of the most beautiful schools. The door was open and so I went in. My husband and daughter standing outside and watching, as again there was No Trespassing signs posted. I came outside to find them talking with a white woman who said she and her fox hunting group owned the property, which I learned later was not the case. I found some information on the school and it listed the family who actually did own the school and property and whose relatives had attended the school. I sent the owners some photos and we have stayed in touch. I came home one day to find a box of pecans sent to me as a thank you for the photos. The pecans came from a tree on the property where the school stands."
    - Cecil JR Brown Rosenwald School, 2014
      The school had been broken up at one point and turned into apartments.
    - Cecil JR Brown Rosenwald School, 2007
    - Cecil JR Brown Rosenwald School, 2007
    - Cecil JR Brown Rosenwald School, 2007
    - Cecil JR Brown Rosenwald School, 2007
    - Cecil JR Brown Rosenwald School, 2007
    - Cecil JR Brown Rosenwald School, 2014
    - Cecil JR Brown Rosenwald School, 2014
    - Cecil JR Brown Rosenwald School, 2007
    - Cecil JR Brown Rosenwald School, 2014
    - Cecil JR Brown Rosenwald School, 2007
    - Cecil JR Brown Rosenwald School, 2007
    - Cecil JR Brown Rosenwald School, 2007
  - Chicago, Illinois, 2013-2014; 6; 19 TIFF image files, approximately 0.7 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the Rosenwald Apartments in Chicago. Hoskins writes: "Nat King Cole, Gwendolyn Brooks and Quincy Jones all lived here at one time."
    - Rosenwald Apartments, 47th and Michigan Ave, Chicago, IL, 2013
    - Rosenwald Apartments, 47th and Michigan Ave, Chicago, IL, 2013
    - Rosenwald Apartments, 47th and Michigan Ave, Chicago, IL, 2013
    - Rosenwald Apartments, 47th and Michigan Ave, Chicago, IL, 2013
    - Rosenwald Apartments, 47th and Michigan Ave, Chicago, IL, 2013
    - Rosenwald Apartments, 47th and Michigan Ave, Chicago, IL, 2013
    - Rosenwald Apartments, 47th and Michigan Ave, Chicago, IL, 2013
    - Rosenwald Apartments, 47th and Michigan Ave, Chicago, IL, 2014
    - Rosenwald Apartments, 47th and Michigan Ave, Chicago, IL, 2013
    - Rosenwald Apartments, 47th and Michigan Ave, Chicago, IL, 2014
    - Rosenwald Apartments, 47th and Michigan Ave, Chicago, IL, 2013
    - Rosenwald Apartments, 47th and Michigan Ave, Chicago, IL, 2013
    - Rosenwald Apartments, 47th and Michigan Ave, Chicago, IL, 2013
    - Rosenwald Apartments, 47th and Michigan Ave, Chicago, IL, 2013
    - Rosenwald Apartments, 47th and Michigan Ave, Chicago, IL, 2013
    - Rosenwald Apartments, 47th and Michigan Ave, Chicago, IL, 2014
    - Rosenwald Apartments, 47th and Michigan Ave, Chicago, IL, 2013
    - Rosenwald Apartments, 47th and Michigan Ave, Chicago, IL, 2013
    - Rosenwald Apartments, 47th and Michigan Ave, Chicago, IL, 2013
  - Davies County, Kentucky, 2013-2014; 9; 4 TIFF image files, approximately 0.1 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the Rosenwald school building in Pleasant Ridge, Davies County. The school was moved 35 miles from its original site to the Yellow Creek Park Nature Center.
    - Pleasant Ridge School, 2013
    - Pleasant Ridge School, 2013
    - Pleasant Ridge School, 2014
    - Pleasant Ridge School, 2013
  - Finchville, Kentucky, 2014; 11; 5 TIFF image files, approximately 0.2 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the Buck Creek Rosenwald school building and nearby chapel.
    - Buck Creek Colored School next to Allen Chapel, 2014
    - Allen Chapel next to Buck Creek Colored School, 2014
    - Allen Chapel next to Buck Creek Colored School, 2014
    - Allen Chapel next to Buck Creek Colored School, 2014
    - Buck Creek Colored School next to Allen Chapel, 2014
      This was a case where there was someone home and many No Tresspassing signs did not allow me to get as close.
  - Fort Springs, Kentucky, 2012; 12; 1 JPEG image file, approximately 0.1 gigabytes.
    The image in this subseries documents the Rosenwald school building in Fort Springs. It is situated behind a Baptist church and used for church gatherings at the time this photograph was taken.
    - Fort Springs Rosenwald School behind New Vine Baptist Chuch, 2012
  - Mason County, Kentucky, 2013-2014; 21; 7 TIFF image files, approximately 0.2 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the May's Lick Negro School Rosenwald building.
    - May's Lick Rosenwald School, 2013
    - May's Lick Rosenwald School, 2013
    - May's Lick Rosenwald School, 2014
    - May's Lick Rosenwald School, 2013
    - May's Lick Rosenwald School, 2013
    - May's Lick Rosenwald School, 2013
  - Maddoxtown, Kentucky, 2012; 19; 1 TIFF file, approximately 0.1 gigabytes.
    Scope
    The image in this subseries documents the Rosenwald school building in Maddoxtown, Kentucky. At the time this image was taken, the building was used as a home. Hoskins writes: "I know both students and teachers who went and taught here and confrimed that this was the school it has been a home for a very long time."
    - Maddoxtown Rosenwald School, 2012
  - Mercer County, Kentucky, 2012; 22; 15 TIFF image files, approximately 0.5 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the Mayo Rosenwald school in Mercer County, Kentucky. Hoskins writes: "The images in color here where not from my first visit to this community. I originally went there with my friend MaryAnn Meaux. She had told me about her uncle who was the last African American in the hamlet and that he was having an auction of all of his things and invited me to come and photograph. He was going to be moving into town or a nursing home. I do not remember which but I do remember the rain. It was pouring for most of the day. I also remember I saw him in his truck watching the auction and crying. There are photos of all of this from The Homeplace project. That is how I learned about this school. The school as not far from where the auction was. Like many it was next to a church. This church is loosing its members at a rapid pace as the elders are passing away. As for now on my last trip both school and church are standing in good shape."
    - Mayo Rosenwald School, 2012
    - Mayo Rosenwald School Outhouse, 2012
    - Mayo Rosenwald School, 2012
    - Mayo Rosenwald School, 2012
    - Mayo Rosenwald School, 2012
      The School is on the left the Dividing Ridge Baptist Church is on the right.
    - Mayo Rosenwald School, 2012
    - Mayo Rosenwald School, 2012
    - Mayo Rosenwald School, 2012
    - Mayo Rosenwald School, 2012
    - Mayo Rosenwald School, 2012
    - Mayo Rosenwald School, 2012
    - Mayo Rosenwald School interior through window, 2012
    - Mayo Rosenwald School, 2012
    - Mayo Rosenwald School, 2012
    - Mayo Rosenwald School, 2012
  - Gallatin County, Kentucky, 2008-2014; 13; 7 TIFF image files, approximately 0.2 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the Park Ridge Rosenwald school building in Gallatin County, Kentucky. Hoskins writes: "I learned about this school from Moe Ware. I met him at Maddoxtown Baptist Church photographing The Homeplace project. He had grown up in this community and took me to photograph the school. At one time it was a pretty thriving black hamlet but like several communities all that is left is the church and if lucky the school as is the case here."
    - Park Ridge Rosenwald School, 2011
    - Church next to Park Ridge Rosenwald School, 2014
      Hoskins included this as the church doors are much the same for many of the churches next to the schools.
    - Park Ridge Rosenwald School, 2008
    - Park Ridge Rosenwald (background), 2008
    - Park Ridge Rosenwald (background), 2008
    - Park Ridge Rosenwald School, 2008
    - Side of Park Ridge Rosenwald School and church, 2008
  - Garrard County, Kentucky, 2013-2014; 14; 31 TIFF image files, approximately 1.1 gigabytes.